<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Health and Safety Training Courses in North Lanarkshire]]></title><description><![CDATA[Health and Safety Training Courses by experts at Graham Hendry Training & Consultancy Services in North Lanarkshire, Scotland. Call us on 07960 325 514]]></description><link>http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 05:17:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[C.O.S.H.H.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/coshh.jpg' class='img-responsive'><p><strong>Control of Substances Hazardous to Health</strong></p>
<p>Understanding COSHH is vital to anyone using, handling or disposing of chemicals.</p>
<p>The COSHH Data Sheet contains information regarding use, protection, First Aid and safe disposal.</p>
<p>The proactive driver for safe use of chemicals has always come through accident investigations but more recently through compliance documents such as ISO14001 (Environmental Management Systems).</p>
<p>The over-riding objective is always to identity safer products that don’t need a COSHH Data Sheet, basically applying the first recommended step in risk assessment: ‘remove the hazard’.</p>
<p>The alternative is to depend on the human application of a safe system of work for using and controlling the hazardous chemical.</p>
<p>When using hazardous chemicals, training in their use and understanding of the nature of the hazard are vital. The safe system of work must clearly identify the negative outcome that will result on both the person using the product and the surrounding environment.</p>
<p>Non-compliance with COSHH regulations will leave you open to criminal prosecution through the Health &amp; Safety at Work Act.</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/c-o-s-h-h</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/c-o-s-h-h</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/coshh.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Turning Risk Assessment on its head]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/tra-cover.jpg' class='img-responsive'><p>  I’d like to share a Research Article from Mr Rosness Ragnar, SINTEF Norway <a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/14773996.2016.1255443">http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/14773996.2016.1255443</a></p>
<p>The common approach for Risk Assessment (RA) is to focus on the higher risk practices and input rules to develop a ‘Suitable and Sufficient’ RA.</p>
<p>This article turns that thinking on its head by analysing ‘Successful Operations’ instead.</p>
<p>By their nature, successful operations (as defined in the article, don’t confuse it with being lucky!) will be suitable and sufficient.</p>
<p>Analysing successful operations doesn’t necessarily come naturally, when nothing adverse happens it passes off as a ‘non-event’ but the objective is to look at why the operation was successful and find the many things that actually did happen to prevent failure and create your method statement accordingly.</p>
<p>The focus moves from what history or common practise tells us should be done to what is already working.</p>
<p>So, in summary, if you focus on your success you’ll continue to be successful.</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/turning-risk-assessment-on-its-head</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/turning-risk-assessment-on-its-head</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/tra-cover.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Safeguarding Adults & Children]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/security-cover.jpg' class='img-responsive'><p><strong>Historic Child Abuse, how can you help to stop this rot?</strong></p>
<p>The world of Football has been rocked by the shameful actions of a few, ask yourself; what could you do to avoid this happening in your industry?</p>
<p>Few recognise situations that leave the vulnerable at risk so protective procedures never get considered.</p>
<p>Organisations don’t seem to know they’ve failed the vulnerable until a scandal breaks, then it’s too late.</p>
<p><strong>Your options?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><p>You could do nothing (and hope)</p>
</li>
<li><p>You could be proactive; create a robust Safeguarding Policy and train your staff so you’ll discourage these unsavoury characters from starting or continuing their vile trade under your nose.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>There’s a moral obligation to look out for the vulnerable but there’s also a legal obligation.</p>
<p>Failure to address your moral obligations in business will leave your company reputation in tatters.</p>
<p>Failure to comply with your legal obligations will find you in the criminal court and, later, the civil court.</p>
<p>Take the initiative, get Safeguarding on your next agenda, get a policy, train your staff and sleep easier at night.</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/safeguarding-adults-children</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/safeguarding-adults-children</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/security-cover.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[E Learning, it's here now!]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/e-learning-cover.jpg' class='img-responsive'><p><strong>It’s fast,     </strong>           <strong>It’s convenient,     </strong>          <strong>It’s been proven to work</strong></p>
<p>An email to your desk top, tablet or smart phone and start studying.</p>
<p>The learning is positive, enlightening and enjoyable.</p>
<p>We might never replace the classroom, but, when the subject permits or where the workers are remote; E Learning comes into its own.</p>
<p>E Learning has changed, you now get video lead interactive involvement, real persons and cartoons holding the attention and getting desired learning outcomes.</p>
<p><strong>How it’s changed:</strong></p>
<p>H&amp;S E Learning examples:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fire Marshal, you’ll get the Legal stuff then, using cartoons &amp; real life video, you’ll feel and observe the real human responses during evacuations and get the confidence and knowledge to carry out a Fire Drill, a Fire Report and identify best practice.</li>
<li>Display Screen Equipment, you again get the Legal stuff then comprehensive info regarding Musculoskeletal disorders and solutions.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What does the future hold?</strong></p>
<p>Virtual Reality (VR) programs.</p>
<p>VR is expensive, but technological advances will surely bring prices down.</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/e-learning-it-s-here-now</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/e-learning-it-s-here-now</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/e-learning-cover.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Health & Safety After Brexit]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/has-cover.jpg' class='img-responsive'><p>  Questions about an uncertain future of H&amp;S regulation after BREXIT;</p>
<p>Will continue in the status quo?</p>
<p>Will become more burdensome?</p>
<p>Will be diluted?</p>
<p>The only answer at this stage can be “Not sure”</p>
<p>Before jumping to conclusions, there are facts and history relative to H&amp;S in the UK worth considering</p>
<p>Since H&amp;S regulation began, the UK has had most robust regulation in the world</p>
<p>Misconceptions about the best H&amp;S standards; not Sweden (Volvo’s reputation?) or Germany (modern manufacturing and reliable transport systems)</p>
<p>We shouldn’t make assumptions but wouldn’t it be reasonable to suggest that, given our reputation for placing a high value on H&amp;S, it would continue as a ‘natural response’?</p>
<p>The European Norms were developed mostly from existing British Standards</p>
<p>Recent revisions of the Health and Safety at Work Act 1974 were carried out by the UK Government, not the European Government</p>
<p>In summary, it’s unlikely that a UK Government would look to undo the robust regulation in favour of untried or diluted alternatives  Questions about an uncertain future of H&amp;S regulation after BREXIT;</p>
<p>Will continue in the status quo?</p>
<p>Will become more burdensome?</p>
<p>Will be diluted?</p>
<p>The only answer at this stage can be “Not sure”</p>
<p>Before jumping to conclusions, there are facts and history relative to H&amp;S in the UK worth considering</p>
<p>Since H&amp;S regulation began, the UK has had most robust regulation in the world</p>
<p>Misconceptions about the best H&amp;S standards; not Sweden (Volvo’s reputation?) or Germany (modern manufacturing and reliable transport systems)</p>
<p>We shouldn’t make assumptions but wouldn’t it be reasonable to suggest that, given our reputation for placing a high value on H&amp;S, it would continue as a ‘natural response’?</p>
<p>The European Norms were developed mostly from existing British Standards</p>
<p>Recent revisions of the Health and Safety at Work Act 1974 were carried out by the UK Government, not the European Government</p>
<p>In summary, it’s unlikely that a UK Government would look to undo the robust regulation in favour of untried or diluted alternatives</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/health-safety-after-brexit</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/health-safety-after-brexit</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/has-cover.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>CDATA[How to fill in a Security Application form]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src='http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/howtofeel-sec-form.jpg' class='img-responsive'><h5 id="it-sounds-condescending-but-in-years-of-recruiting-i-ve-seen-so-many-applications-go-in-the-bin-because-they-are-incomplete-">It sounds condescending but, in years of recruiting, I’ve seen so many applications go in the bin because they are incomplete!</h5>
<p><strong>Security companies need to comply with <em>BS 7858:2012</em> Security screening of individuals employed in a security environment</strong></p>
<p>Why comply? Insurance, Association Membership, Industry Standards such as Approved Contractor (ACS), other British Standards and SIA Licensing Regulations all depend on compliance.</p>
<p><strong>The basic elements are:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>5 yr history of home addresses, to complete a DBS checks. The disclosure will confirm your addresses’ and confirm unspent criminal convictions</li>
<li>5 years employment, self employment, unemployment history</li>
<li>Any unconfirmed dates will be queried and will hinder any offer of employment</li>
<li>A Credit Check is carried out to identify any CCJs</li>
<li>Character References, most companies will ask for two. They will confirm they have known you for the previous 2 years but preferably 5. Referees can’t be relatives or living at the same address</li>
</ul>
]]></description><link>http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/how-to-fill-in-a-security-application-form</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/blog/how-to-fill-in-a-security-application-form</guid><category><![CDATA[blog]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://www.hendry-training.buzzin.today/img/blog/featured/howtofeel-sec-form.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>